Igor Shevayhov

The Full Stack Web Developer

Russian Federation, Saratov region, Engels, Turgeneva 34/3 +1(912) 324-4689
CHEESEOOOOK@GMAIL.COM

ACHIEVEMENT

I am not just a developer with over a decade of experience in developing web apps, mobile apps and a range of other technical skills (search, scientific computing and more). – I understand business with a lot of experience working for CME and startups (both as employer and contractor).

I know a LOT about what will make mobile apps and web apps deliver your business objectives rather than just look pretty. - I produce code of exceptional quality

I have fixed a lot of other developer's code since I became a freelancer and can not recall any who are better than me, and very few who are as good.

I have a strong academic background with a master degree. – I also put a lot of effort into updating and improving my skills.

I also advise on mobile and web software development, helping clients reduce execution risk, refine their concepts, and provide developers with precise specifications.

EXPERIENCE

Back-End Developer

Angel.co

Remote

January 2011 - February 2013

Very capable on BUG_FIXING and Tweaks of any kind

Be passionate about new technology.

Strong experience in mobile app development.

Extensive experience in front-end and back-end of websites.

Full Stack Developer

oDesk & Elance-oDesk

Remote

January 2012 - September 2014

Keep well deadline of each project

SKILLS

SCRIPT LANGUAGE

JavaScript / ES5 / ES6

Typescript / CoffeeScript

jQuery / jQueryUI

PHP / PHP5 / PHP7

Python / Pythons

Ruby

HTML / HTML5 / CSS / CSSs, BOOTStrap

FRAMEWORKS FOR WEB DEVELOPMENT

React/Redux, Vue/Vuex, AngularJS/2/4/5+

Rails

Django

Laravel5/Codeigniter/CakePhp/O pencart

Loopback and backbone js

CMS

Shopify/Wordpress/Magento/Sy mfony

PWA/SPA DEVELOPMENT

MOTION UX/UI DESIGN

MODULE BUNDLER

WebPack/Gulp/Grunt/Babel

VERSION CONTROL SYSTEM

GitHub/BitBucket

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

TOOL

Asana/Trello/Jira/Monday

Strong interpersonal skills.

Excellent public relations skills: work well with partners, co-workers, and designers.

Able to match team members with project assignments.

CRM & WEBSITE DEVELOPER

Freelancer.com

Remote

January 2015 - Present

Created and proofread CRM & CMS for top-level company executives.

Experience in CRM development or CRM customization.

Successful IT professional with management and programming experience.

Extensive experience in front-end and back-end of websites.

PROJECTS

WRITING WITH DESIGN http://www.writingwithdesign.com/

Writing with Design is a revolutionary approach to writing, designed by teachers for teachers.

We believe that powerful resources, stellar training and meaningful feedback allow teachers to confidently teach writing in any subject.

I worked as a full-stack developer.

05/2017 - 9/2017 GARTAN TECHNOLOGIES ROLE AS PROJECT MANAGER AND DEVELOPER

https://gartantech.com

Developed Wordpress websites by using page builder, revolution slider.

STEPHAN LEGRAND ROLE AS PROJECT MANAGER AND DEVELOPER OUTDOOR PHOTOGRAPHY

https://stephanelegrand.com

Developed Wordpress websites by using page builder, resolution sliders.

02/2016 - 06/2016 ITAILOR, ROLE AS PROJECT MANAGER AND DEVELOPER

https://www.italior.com

TESTING TOOL

Jasmine, Karma

WEB-SERVICES

Nginx/Apache/Oracle

WEB HOSTING

AWS/Digital Ocean

DESIGN PATTERN

MVC/MVVM

OTHER TECHNOLOGIES

 ${\tt TCP, IP/HTTP, HTTPS/SMTP/Elast}$

ic Search Engine/Web Scraping/Web Socket

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Applications - MCA, Computer and Information Sciences and Support Services

Dalian University of Technology

LANGUAGES

Russian, English

Developed awesome Ecommerce websites.

07/2015 - 12/2015 FASHIONNOVA (SHOPIFY WEBSITES AND THEME), ROLE AS PROJECT MANAGER AND DEVELOPER

https://www.fashionnova.com

Developed Shopify websites and development of themes.

03/2011 - 04/2012 TAILOR VINTAGE, ROLE AS PROJECT MANAGER AND DEVELOPER

https://tailorvintage.com

BELLAMI HAIR ROLE AS PROJECT MANAGER AND DEVELOPER

https://www.bellamihair.com

ZONORY (RUBY ON RAILS), ROLE AS PROJECT MANAGER AND DEVELOPER

https://www.zenory.com

Implemented the back-end of websites which have only front-end ruby on rails.

AXANYA (PHP, LARAVEL FRAMEWORK), ROLE AS PROJECT MANAGER AND DEVELOPER

https://axanya.com

SPEEVR (PYTHON SERVICE + LARAVEL BACKEND), ROLE AS PROJECT MANAGER AND DEVELOPER

https://www.speevr.com

FOXYBLU (CODEIGNITER FRAMEWORK & PAYMENT INTEGRATION & SOCIAL WEBSITE), ROLE AS PROJECT MANAGER AND DEVELOPER

https://dev.foxyblu.com

RACING HORSE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM, ROLE AS PROJECT MANAGER AND DEVELOPER

https://dev.theracingmanager.com

(demovitaminlondon.com Demo12)

Racing Horse Management system is a web application based on React

and Redux.

All horses and competition schedules are managed by the system.

NUDGG BITCOIN WEBAPP This project was made using ReactJS, Redux, Redux-thunk and so on.

In this project, I was a front-end developer.

02/2016 - 06/2016 BEACON, ROLE AS PROJECT MANAGER AND DEVELOPER

Beacon is a web application based on Vue/Vuex, D3.js/Three.js for DataVisualization.

I helped the website scale from 10K views/day to 100K views/day.

07/2015 - 12/2015 COINIGY, ROLE AS PROJECT MANAGER AND DEVELOPER

COINIGY is a web application based on React and Redux.

03/2011 - 04/2012 TAXI WEB APPLICATIONS WEB APPLICATION FOR TAXI BUSINESS & PASSENGERS (MAEN)

https://www.onlinetaxi.co.za

People can find and book taxis, book taxis and pay for trips.

Taxi businesses can register themselves and manage drivers, booking, financial transactions, etc.

It's been built with Angular and Node.

I worked as a full stack MEAN developer.

STUDENTS - TEACHERS - PARENTS COLLABORATION WEBSITE https://www.myperfectice.com

This is a website where students, teachers and parents can collaborate to improve the learning and examination process.

Built with MEAN stack. I played the role of full stack developer.

EDUCATION WEBSITE

https://spoonfeedme.com.au

This is a website that serves video courses, notes and cheat sheets to university students.

It;s been built with a MEAN stack.

I participated in the project as a full stack developer.

ARTIST BOOKING WEBSITE (REACT + NODE) HTTPS://PARLOURGIGS.COM

This is a website where you can book artists, sell tickets, pay artists and so on.

It's been built with ReactJS and NodeJS.

I was a lead developer and worked on both frontend and backend.

DATA ANALYTICS APPLICATION HTTPS://WWW.WMSIGHT.COM

Data analytics application built with ReactJS.

LANGUAGE LEARNING PLATFORM (REACT + NODE) HTTPS://WWW.VERBLING.COM

This is a ReactJS web application connecting language learners and teachers.

Learners can find native speakers who registered to teach their language.

I participated in the project as a full stack developer.

Banner Maker

https://bigpla.net/banner-19/auth

Bannersnack is an all-in-one toolkit for your online advertising needs. The user interface is user-friendly, making it easy even for non-designers to create professional-level banner designs.

It was built with ReactJs, FabricJs, PHP, etc.

I participated in the project as a full stack developer.